## Patrick Hoehn

Broomfield, Co, 80021 | 815-441-4279 | ThePatrickHoehn@gmail.com github.com/meniality | patrickhoehn.dev | linkedin.com/in/patrick-hoehn-0a1238197/

### **Software Engineer**

Full stack web developer with experience in Ruby and JavaScript programming languages with a background in retail operations and customer service. Has a strong, detailed, and organized approach to performing job duties. Self motivated individual that excels working in a collaborative team environment. Board game enthusiast and professional tech student - able to quickly learn and adjust to an ever changing environment to optimize personal output and efficiency.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javscript, React, React Native, Photoshop, Corel, SASS, HTML

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

DM Mapper - youtube.com/watch?v=yAn3X77H940

github.com/meniality/DmMapper | github.com/meniality/DmMapperBackEnd

Allows users to build a fantasy world in an organized and easily traversable fashion.

- JSON Web Tokens and Bcrypt to encrypt the users information both server and client side.
- ActiveRecord to create complex table relationships on the backend server.
- React Hooks to reduce unnecessary classes and improve readability.

## BibFox - youtube.com/watch?v=ZT6jnVjRpR0

github.com/meniality/library-share-frontend | github.com/meniality/library share backend

Allows users to build and maintain a virtual shelf of books that they currently own and find the locations of library share kiosks.

- Google Maps API and Google-Map-React library to customize the visuals of Google Maps.
- SASS to organize and improve the readability of CSS styling.
- React Router to give the appearance of a multi-page app.
- Followed the MVC architectural pattern and RESTful routing conventions

# Board Game MeetUp - <u>youtube.com/watch?v=KafJbb7Uj0c</u>

github.com/meniality/BoardGameMeetupFrontend | github.com/meniality/BoardGameMeetupBackend

Brief description of the app's functionality and purpose

- Custom built RESTful API backend to store information
- Built in Vanilla JS to understand JS fundamentals

### **EXPERIENCE**

Engraver, The Watch Movement, Denver, Co. 06/2018 - present

Business partner and watch and jewelry engraver

Shipping and Receiving Asst., Hyde Park, Denver, Co. 06/2018 - 10/2019

 Oversaw and processed all incoming and outgoing jewelry for the companies 4 locations while maintaining detailed records due to high value of items

Operations Manager, **Shane Co**, Greenwood Village, Co. 06/2014 - 06/2018

- Trained and managed the Customer Service team to provide excellent service. Planned and executed team events to build morale and to reduce turnover.
- Managed over \$7 Million of store merchandise including weekly inventories and Sales associate training on proper handling and processes.
- Oversaw shipping processes to ensure accuracy and efficiency.

### **EDUCATION**

### Flatiron School 10/2019 - 03/2020

Fully immersive 15 week, in person, full time 9-5 programming course that taught the methodology of Full Stack Web Development utilizing Ruby on Rails and JavaScript/React program languages.

#### **Quantum Helicopters** 04/2014 - 06/2014

Full time student. Obtained private helicopter license.